Register of the Poland. Poselstwo (Portugal) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- SERIES NO. 341a. POLITICAL PUBLICATIONS
  - 1933 (Folder 16: 9)
  - 1934
    - Pilsudski, Jozef (Folder 16: 10)
    - Portugal's constitution (Folder 16: 11)
  - 1935 (Folder 16: 12)
  - 1936 - Ferro, Antonio (Folder 16: 13)
  - 1937 - Polish-Czechoslovak relations (Folder 16: 14)
  - 1938 (Folder 16: 15)
  - 1939 (Folder 16: 16)
  - 1940 (Folder 16: 17)
  - 1943-1944. (Folder 16: 18)
    Includes Fight for Freedom Memorandum, with an article on the influence of President Wilson's declaration on Germany in 1918
- SERIES NO. 341b. ECONOMIC PUBLICATIONS
  - 1935 (Folder 16: 19)
  - 1936 (Folder 16: 20)
  - 1938 (Folder 16: 21)
  - 1939 (Folder 16: 22)
- SERIES NO. 341c. SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS
  - 1934 (Folder 16: 23)
  - 1936 (Folder 16: 24)
  - 1939 - Zaolzie (Box-folder 17: 1)
- SERIES NO. 341d. CULTURAL PUBLICATIONS
  - 1935-1936 (Folder 17: 2)
  - 1936 - Publishing (Folder 17: 3)
  - 1937 (Folder 17: 4)
  - 1938 (Folder 17: 5)
  - 1939 (Folder 17: 6)
- SERIES NO. 341e. TOURIST PUBLICATIONS
  - 1936 (Folder 17: 7)
  - 1939 (Folder 17: 8)
- SERIES NO. 342b. FOREIGN PUBLICATIONS ON POLAND, 1939 (Folder 17: 9)
- SERIES NO. 346. TOURISM RELATED ISSUES, 1934
  - General (Folder 17: 10)
  - Nowak, Kazimierz (Folder 17: 11)
- SERIES NO. 348. TRIPS, 1938 (Folder 17: 12)
- SERIES NO. 348a. TRIPS ABROAD FROM POLAND
  - 1934 (Folder 17: 13)
  - 1935
    - General (Folder 17: 14)
    - MS Pilsudski (Folder 17: 15)
    - SS Kosciuszko (Folder 17: 16)
  - 1939 (Folder 17: 17)
- SERIES NO. 349a. TRAVELS OF POLES GOING ABROAD - Wrzos, Konrad, 1936 (Folder 17: 18)
- SERIES NO. 349b. TRAVELS OF FOREIGNERS COMING TO POLAND - Ferro, Antonio (Folder 17: 19)
- SERIES NO. 350. PROPAGANDA INSTITUTIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS, 1934 (Folder 17: 20)
- SERIES NO. 350a. PROPAGANDA INSTITUTIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS IN POLAND
  - 1933 (Folder 17: 21)
  - 1935 (Folder 17: 22)
  - 1939 - Gdansk. (Folder 17: 23)
    Bibliography
- SERIES NO. 350b. PROPAGANDA INSTITUTIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS ABROAD, 1939 (Folder 17: 24)
- SERIES NO. 351a. POLISH-FOREIGN ASSOCIATIONS IN POLAND - Sociedade Polaco-Portugeza, 1935 (Folder 17: 25)
- SERIES NO. 351b. POLISH-FOREIGN ASSOCIATIONS ABROAD - Grupo Amigade Luso-Polaca (Folder 17: 26)
- SERIES NO. 353. ACADEMIC ASSOCIATIONS, 1939 (Folder 17: 27)
- SERIES NO. 359. LEGISLATURE, CONGRESSES, CONFERENCES, INTERNATIONAL MEETINGS, 1934-1935 (Folder 17: 28)
- SERIES NO. 360. INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATIONS, ORGANIZATIONS, UNIONS
  - 1934 (Folder 17: 29)
  - 1939 (Folder 17: 30)
- SERIES NO. 362a. POLISH TRANSPORTATION COMPANIES
  - 1934 (Folder 17: 31)
  - 1935 (Folder 17: 32)
  - 1936 (Folder 17: 33)
  - 1938 (Folder 17: 34)
  - 1939 (Folder 17: 35)
- SERIES NO. 363c. INTERNATIONAL TRANSPORTATION COMPANIES, 1938 (Folder 17: 36)
- SERIES NO. 367. NAVIGATION
  - 1938 (Folder 17: 37)
  - 1939 (Folder 17: 38)
  - 1944 (Folder 17: 39)
  - 1945 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- SERIES NO. 367a. SEA NAVIGATION
  - 1935 (Folder 18: 2)
  - 1936 (Folder 18: 3)
  - 1939 - Mobilization and air raids protocols (Folder 18: 4)
- SERIES NO. 368. PORTS AND DUTY FREE ZONES
  - 1935 (Folder 18: 5)
  - 1936 (Folder 18: 6)
- SERIES NO. 371. AVIATION
  - 1934 (Folder 18: 7)
  - 1945 (Folder 18: 8)
- SERIES NO. 371a. POLISH AVIATION
  - 1925 (Folder 18: 9)
  - 1932-1933 - Purchase of airplanes by Portugal (Folder 18: 10)
  - 1933 - Idzikowski, Kubala, Karpinski (Folder 18: 11)
  - 1935 (Folder 18: 12)
  - 1939 - Balloon competition (Folder 18: 13)
- SERIES NO. 371b. FOREIGN AVIATION - Portugal
  - 1928 (Folder 18: 14)
  - 1939
    - KLM (Folder 18: 15)
    - United States (Folder 18: 16)
- SERIES NO. 372b. AIRCRAFT TRANSIT BY POLISH AIRCRAFTS OVER FOREIGN TERRITORY, 1935 (Folder 18: 17)
- SERIES NO. 373b. FOREIGN AIRLINES
  - 1934 (Folder 18: 18)
  - 1935 (Folder 18: 19)
  - 1937 (Folder 18: 20)
- SERIES NO. 375. LIGA OBRONY POWIETRZNEJ PANSTWA (LEAGUE OF STATE'S AIR DEFENSES)
  - 1935
    - General (Folder 18: 21)
    - Burzynski - Wysocki (Folder 18: 22)
  - 1936
    - General (Folder 18: 23)
    - Posters (Folder 18: 24)
  - 1938 (Folder 18: 25)
  - 1939 (Folder 18: 26)
- SERIES NO. 385a. TRANSIT THROUGH POLAND - POMORZE (POMMERN) 1936 (Folder 18: 27)
- SERIES NO. 390a. POLISH SHIPS (Box 19)
  - 1928-1933 (Folder 19: 1)
  - 1934 (Folder 19: 2)
- SERIES NO. 390a. POLISH SHIPS
  - 1935 (Folder 19: 3)
  - 1936 (Folder 19: 4)
  - 1937 (Folder 19: 5)
  - 1938 (Folder 19: 6)
  - 1939 - Iskra (Folder 19: 7)
- SERIES NO. 390b. FOREIGN SHIPS - Germans in Portuguese submarine service, 1928-1930 (Folder 19: 8)
- SERIES NO. 392. MINISTRY OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS. MINISTER. EXPOSES, SPEECHES, DECLARATIONS, INTERVIEWS
  - 1936 - Beck, Jozef
    - January 15 (Folder 19: 9)
    - December 18 (Folder 19: 10)
  - 1938 - Beck, Jozef, January 10 (Folder 19: 11)
  - 1939
    - Beck, Jozef, May 5 (Folder 19: 12)
    - Smigly-Rydz, Edward, August 6 (Folder 19: 13)
  - 1940 (Folder 19: 14)
  - 1943 - Romer, Tadeusz (Folder 19: 15)
  - 1944 (Folder 19: 16)
- SERIES NO. 396. FOREIGN MINISTER. TALKS WITH FOREIGN ENVOYS, 1936 (Folder 19: 17)
- SERIES NO. 397. CORRESPONDENCE OF FOREIGN MINISTER - Jozef Potocki, Jan Tomaszewski, Aleksander Zawisza
  - 1952 (Folder 19: 18)
  - 1954 (Folder 19: 19)
  - 1955 (Folder 19: 20)
  - 1956 (Folder 19: 21)
  - 1957 (Folder 19: 22)
- SERIES NO. 410. TELEGRAMS BETWEEN THE MINISTRY AND POLAND'S FOREIGN REPRESENTATIONS (Box 20)
  - 1933 January - 1935 April - Incoming and outgoing (Folder 20: 1)
  - 1935 April - 1937 September - Incoming and outgoing (Folder 20: 2)
  - 1937 December - 1940 July - Incoming and outgoing (Folder 20: 3)
  - 1940 - Incoming and outgoing
    - July-September (Folder 20: 4)
    - September-December (Folder 20: 5)
  - 1941
    - Incoming
      - January-June (Folder 20: 6)
      - June-December (Folder 20: 7)
    - Outgoing
      - January-June (Folder 20: 8)
      - June-December (Folder 20: 9)
  - 1942 (Box 21)
    - January-June
      - Incoming (Folder 21: 1)
      - Outgoing (Folder 21: 2)
    - July-December
      - Incoming (Folder 21: 3)
      - Outgoing (Folder 21: 4)
- SERIES NO. 410. TELEGRAMS BETWEEN THE MINISTRY AND POLAND'S FOREIGN REPRESENTATIONS
  - 1943
    - General
      - January-June
        - Incoming (Folder 21: 5)
        - Outgoing (Folder 21: 6)
      - July-December
        - Incoming (Folder 21: 7)
        - Outgoing (Folder 21: 8)
    - Coded - Incoming and outgoing (Folder 21: 9)
  - 1944
    - General
      - January-June
        - Incoming (Folder 21: 10)
        - Outgoing (Folder 21: 11)
      - July-December
        - Incoming (Folder 21: 12)
        - Outgoing (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Circulars (Folder 22: 2)
    - Financial reports
      - Incoming (Folder 22: 3)
      - Outgoing (Folder 22: 4)
    - Foreign representations reports
      - Incoming (Folder 22: 5)
      - Outgoing (Folder 22: 6)
  - 1944-1945 - Coded
    - Incoming (Folder 22: 7)
    - Outgoing (Folder 22: 8)
  - 1945
    - General - January-July
      - Incoming (Folder 22: 9)
      - Outgoing (Folder 22: 10)
    - Circulars, January-July (Folder 22: 11)
    - Foreign representations reports, January-December
      - Incoming (Folder 22: 12)
      - Outgoing (Folder 22: 13)
- SERIES NO. 411. DIPLOMATIC PROTOCOLS. CEREMONIES (Box 23)
  - 1934-1935 (Folder 23: 1)
  - 1937 - Countries other than Poland (Folder 23: 2)
  - 1938 - Dubicz-Penther, Karol (Folder 23: 3)
  - 1939 (Folder 23: 4)
- SERIES NO. 412b. FOREIGN CELEBRATIONS AND COMMEMORATIONS
  - 1935 (Folder 23: 5)
  - 1937 (Folder 23: 6)
  - 1938 (Folder 23: 7)
  - 1939 (Folder 23: 8)
- SERIES NO. 413a. POLISH NOTIFICATIONS
  - 1933, July 21 - Szumlakowski, Marian (Folder 23: 9)
  - 1933-1934 - Travel notification (Folder 23: 10)
  - 1936 (Folder 23: 11)
  - 1939 - Raczkiewicz, Wladyslaw (Folder 23: 12)
  - 1940
    - General (Folder 23: 13)
    - Raczkiewicz, Wladyslaw (Folder 23: 14)
- SERIES NO. 413b. FOREIGN NOTIFICATIONS, 1939 (Folder 23: 15)
- SERIES NO. 415a. POLISH EXCHANGE OF GREETINGS, INVITATIONS, CONDOLENCES, 1934-1935 (Folder 23: 16)
- SERIES NO. NO 415b. FOREIGN EXCHANGE OF GREETINGS, INVITATIONS, CONDOLENCES, 1939 (Folder 23: 17)
- SERIES NO. 416a. POLISH MEDALS AND DECORATIONS
  - 1933-1934 - Madeira (Folder 23: 18)
  - 1934-1935 (Folder 23: 19)
  - 1935-1936 (Folder 23: 20)
  - 1937 (Folder 23: 21)
  - 1939 (Folder 23: 22)
  - 1940 (Folder 23: 23)
  - 1943 (Folder 23: 24)
- SERIES NO. 416b. FOREIGN MEDALS AND DECORATIONS
  - 1934 (Folder 23: 25)
  - 1935 (Folder 23: 26)
  - 1936 (Folder 23: 27)
- SERIES NO. 416c. POLISH MEDALS AND DECORATIONS FOR POLES
  - 1938 (Folder 23: 28)
  - 1939 (Folder 23: 29)
- SERIES NO. 416e. POLISH MEDALS AND DECORATIONS. AWARD RULES, 1938 (Folder 23: 30)
- SERIES NO. 416g. POLISH MEDALS AND DECORATIONS. OTHER RELATED ISSUES, 1935-1936 (Folder 23: 31)
- SERIES NO. 417. INFORMATION BANK ON DIPLOMATIC CORPS
  - 1936 (Folder 23: 32)
  - 1938 (Folder 23: 33)
  - 1940 (Folder 23: 34)
- SERIES NO. 419. PRIVATE RADIO STATIONS, 1934 (Folder 23: 35)
- SERIES NO. 420. PRESIDENT OF POLISH REPUBLIC, 1936 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- SERIES NO. 421. MARSHAL JOZEF PILSUDSKI
  - 1933 (Folder 24: 2)
  - 1934
    - Porto (Folder 24: 3)
    - Madeira (Folder 24: 4)
  - 1935
    - General
      - General
        - May
          - General (Folder 24: 5)
          - Beck, Jozef, Telegram from (Folder 24: 6)
        - June (Folder 24: 7)
        - July-August (Folder 24: 8)
        - September-December (Folder 24: 9)
      - Press (Folder 24: 10)
    - Kopiec
      - General (Folder 24: 11)
      - Press (Folder 24: 12)
  - 1936
    - General
      - General (Folder 24: 13)
      - Flyer depicting Jozef Pilsudzki (Folder 24: 14)
    - Kopiec (Folder 24: 15)
    - Madeira (Folder 24: 16)
    - Mass in Lisbon (Folder 24: 17)
- SERIES NO. 422. ORGANIZATION OF DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR RELATIONS, 1937 (Folder 24: 18)
- SERIES NO. 422a. ORGANIZATION OF DIMPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR RELATIONS. POLISH ABROAD
  - 1919 (Folder 24: 19)
  - 1920 (Folder 24: 20)
  - 1922 (Folder 24: 21)
  - 1924. (Box-folder 25: 1)
    Press
- SERIES NO. 423. PERSONNEL OF EMBASSIES AND CONSULATES
  - 1933 - Szumlakowski, Marian (Folder 25: 2)
  - 1935 - Romer, Tadeusz (Folder 25: 3)
  - 1942 (Folder 25: 4)
  - 1945 (Folder 25: 5)
- SERIES NO. 423a. PERSONNEL OF EMBASSIES AND CONSULATES. POLISH ABROAD
  - 1937 (Folder 25: 6)
  - 1941
    - General (Folder 25: 7)
    - "Note verbale" (Folder 25: 8)
  - 1942 - "Note verbale" (Folder 25: 9)
- SERIES NO. 424a. POLISH DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR NETWORK
  - 1920-1923 - Touzet, Ferdinand (Folder 25: 10)
  - 1922-1923 - Lisbon (Folder 25: 11)
  - 1924 (Folder 25: 12)
  - 1924-1930 - Touzet, Ferdinand (Folder 25: 13)
  - 1930 (Folder 25: 14)
  - 1943 (Folder 25: 15)
- SERIES NO. 424b. DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR NETWORK. FOREIGN
  - 1922-1923 (Folder 25: 16)
  - 1935 (Folder 25: 17)
- SERIES NO. 428. HONORARY CONSUL CANDIDATES
  - 1923-1925 (Folder 25: 18)
  - 1924-1932 (Folder 25: 19)
  - 1926-1932 - Lima, Francisco Ferreira de (Folder 25: 20)
  - 1931-1932 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - 1933-1934 (Folder 26: 2)
  - 1933-1935 (Folder 26: 3)
  - 1935-1936 (Folder 26: 4)
  - 1937 (Folder 26: 5)
  - 1938 (Folder 26: 6)
- SERIES NO. 428a. CANDIDATES FOR HONORARY CONSULS - Azores, 1927-1932 (Folder 26: 7)
- SERIES NO. 429. IDENTIFICATION PAPERS, LAISSEZ-PASSERS, PASSPORTS, TRAVEL AND CUSTOMS PROCEDURES, 1940-1945 (Folder 26: 8)
- SERIES NO. 430a. TAXATION, LIVING ACCOMODATIONS, REGISTRATION WITH AUTHORITIES, DRAFT EXEMPTIONS, PERMITS FOR PROPERTY PURCHASES. POLISH AGENCIES ABROAD
  - 1935 (Folder 26: 9)
  - 1938 (Folder 26: 10)
- SERIES NO. 431a. POSTAL SERVICES, TELEGRAPH, TELEPHONE, RADIO ISSUES. POLISH AGENCIES ABROAD, 1936-1937 (Folder 26: 11)
- SERIES NO. 432a. PRIVILEGES OF MINISTRIES OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS OF OTHER COUNTRIES, 1935 (Folder 26: 12)
- SERIES NO. 433. POLICE AND COURT CASES
  - 1935
    - Assault on legation (Folder 26: 13)
    - Police and court cases, demonstrations (Folder 26: 14)
    - Rent (Folder 26: 15)
  - 1936 - Rent
    - General (Folder 26: 16)
    - Court trial (Folder 26: 17)
  - 1936-1938 (Folder 26: 18)
  - 1943 (Folder 26: 19)
- SERIES NO. 436. MINISTRY OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS ORGANIZATIONAL STATUSES, 1940 (Folder 26: 20)
- SERIES NO. 437. INTERNAL REGULATIONS AND INSTRUCTIONS, 1938 (Folder 26: 21)
- SERIES NO. 439. CIRCULARS, 1938-1940 (Folder 26: 22)
- SERIES NO. 447. OFFICE POLICIES, 1940 (Folder 26: 23)
- SERIES NO. 474. OFFICE CLERKS
  - 1927-1939 - Paszkiewicz, Marjan (Folder 26: 24)
  - 1937-1938
    - Brudzinski, Zygmunt (Folder 26: 25)
    - Cianciara, T. (Folder 26: 26)
    - Souza Pereira Cabral, Francisco de (Folder 26: 27)
    - Szmejko, Bohdan (Folder 26: 28)
    - Vieira, Luiz de Castro (Folder 26: 29)
  - 1940 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - 1944 (Folder 27: 2)
  - 1945
    - General (Folder 27: 3)
    - Zilberman, Rita (Folder 27: 4)
- SERIES NO. 474a. FULL-TIME EMPLOYEES, 1939 (Folder 27: 5)
- SERIES NO. 476a. LOWER ADMINISTRATION. FULL-TIME EMPLOYEES - Kotecki, Jan, 1925-1939 (Folder 27: 6)
- SERIES NO. 477. EMPLOYEES OF OTHER MINISTRIES ASSIGNED TO THE MINISTRY OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS, 1941-1944. (Folder 27: 7)
  Includes references to Aleksander Lubienski
- SERIES NO. 478. VARIOUS PERSONAL MATTERS
  - 1936 (Folder 27: 8)
  - 1938 (Folder 27: 9)
  - 1940 (Folder 27: 10)
  - 1940-1941 - Kowalewski, Jan (Folder 27: 11)
  - 1941
    - General (Folder 27: 12)
    - Visas and social assistance (Folder 27: 13)
  - 1942 (Folder 27: 14)
  - 1943
    - General (Folder 27: 15)
    - Visa policy (Folder 27: 16)
  - 1943-1944 - Parnicki, Teodor (Folder 27: 17)
  - 1944. (Folder 27: 18)
    Includes material on August Hlond
  - 1945 (Folder 27: 19)
  - 1946-1949 (Folder 27: 20)
- SERIES NO. 501.DZIENNIK URZEDOWY M.S.Z., 1938 (Folder 27: 21)
- SERIES NO. 507. DIPLOMATIC PASSPORTS
  - 1942 (Folder 27: 22)
  - 1944 (Folder 27: 23)
- SERIES NO. 508. PASSPORTS TO PERFORM PROFESSIONAL DUTIES ABROAD (Box 28)
  - 1940 (Folder 28: 1)
  - 1942 (Folder 28: 2)
  - 1943 (Folder 28: 3)
  - 1944 (Folder 28: 4)
- SERIES NO. 509. VARIOUS PASSPORT ISSUES, 1938 (Folder 28: 5)
- SERIES NO. 512. RECOMMENDATIONS FOR VISA ISSUANCE TO FOREIGN REPRESENTATIONS, 1945 (Folder 28: 6)
- SERIES NO. 516. COURIER MAIL
  - 1940-1942 - Evacuation of ministry's archives and army officers (Folder 28: 7)
  - 1945 (Folder 28: 8)
- SERIES NO. 530. INVENTORY
  - 1935 (Folder 28: 9)
  - 1936 (Folder 28: 10)
  - 1939 (Folder 28: 11)
- SERIES NO. 532. CAPITAL EXPENDITURES OF POLAND'S REPRESENTATIONS ABROAD, 1939 (Folder 28: 12)
- SERIES NO. 537. SALARIES
  - 1939 - Payroll (Folder 28: 13)
  - 1940-1941 - Military personnel and former employees (Folder 28: 14)
- SERIES NO. 540. MEANS OF TRANSPORTATION
  - 1933-1934 (Folder 28: 15)
  - 1935 (Folder 28: 16)
  - 1936
    - General (Folder 28: 17)
    - Inventory (Folder 28: 18)
  - 1940 (Folder 28: 19)
  - 1941 (Folder 29: 1)
  - 1942 (Folder 29: 2)
  - 1944 (Folder 29: 3)
  - 1945 (Folder 29: 4)
- SERIES NO. 551. SOURCES OF TREASURY INCOMES, 1936 (Folder 29: 5)
- SERIES NO. 552. TRANSITORY DEPOSITS
  - 1938 (Folder 29: 6)
  - 1939 (Folder 29: 7)
  - 1940
    - January-June (Folder 29: 8)
    - July-October (Folder 29: 9)
    - November-December (Folder 29: 10)
  - 1941
    - January-March (Folder 29: 11)
    - April-June (Folder 29: 12)
    - July-September (Folder 29: 13)
    - October-December (Folder 29: 14)
  - 1942 (Box 30)
    - January-May (Folder 30: 1)
    - June-August (Folder 30: 2)
    - September-December (Folder 30: 3)
  - 1943
    - January-June (Folder 30: 4)
    - July-December (Folder 30: 5)
  - 1944
    - January-June (Folder 30: 6)
    - July-December (Folder 30: 7)
  - 1945 (Folder 30: 8)
- SERIES NO. 553. DEPOSITS
  - 1940 (Folder 30: 9)
  - 1941- Intercepted courier mail (Folder 30: 10)
  - 1942 (Folder 30: 11)
  - 1943 (Folder 30: 12)
- SERIES NO. 554. ASSIGNMENT OF BUDGETARY SUMS TO REPRESENTATIONS ABROAD
  - 1938 (Folder 30: 13)
  - 1939 (Folder 30: 14)
  - 1940 (Folder 30: 15)
- SERIES NO. 558. PRELIMINARY BUDGET AND RELATED MATERIALS, 1933-1934 (Folder 30: 16)
- SERIES NO. 560. ISSUES RELATED TO BUDGET AND ACCOUNTING
  - 1939 (Folder 30: 17)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- SERIES NO. 564. RECEIPTS
  - 1938
    - January-April (Folder 31: 2)
    - May-August (Folder 31: 3)
    - September-December (Folder 31: 4)
  - 1939
    - January-April (Folder 31: 5)
    - May-August (Folder 31: 6)
    - September-December (Folder 31: 7)
  - 1940 (Folder 31: 8)
  - 1941 (Folder 31: 9)
  - 1942 (Folder 31: 10)
  - 1943
    - General (Folder 31: 11)
    - January-April (Folder 31: 12)
    - May-August (Box-folder 32: 1)
    - September-December (Folder 32: 2)
  - 1944
    - January-April (Folder 32: 3)
    - May-April (Folder 32: 4)
    - September-December (Folder 32: 5)
  - 1944-1945 (Folder 32: 6)
  - 1945-1950 (Folder 32: 7)
- SERIES NO. 634. ORGANIZATION, PERSONNEL, BUDGET, ACCOUNTING, FINANCES OF POLISH DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR REPRESENTATIONS. PORTUGAL, LISBON LEGATION
  - 1933-1934 (Folder 32: 8)
  - 1935 (Folder 32: 9)
  - 1936 (Folder 32: 10)
  - 1938 (Folder 32: 11)
  - 1939 (Folder 32: 12)
  - 1940 (Folder 32: 13)
  - 1941 (Folder 32: 14)
  - 1942
    - General (Folder 32: 15)
    - January-April (Folder 32: 16)
    - May-August (Folder 32: 17)
    - September-December (Folder 32: 18)
  - 1943 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - 1944 (Folder 33: 2)
- SERIES NO. 667. HONORARY CONSULATES
  - 1933 (Folder 33: 3)
  - 1934 (Folder 33: 4)
- SERIES NO. 674. AUTHORIZATIONS FOR CONSULS, 1933-1938 (Folder 33: 5)
- SERIES NO. 676. CONSULAR MEETINGS
  - 1933
    - General (Folder 33: 6)
    - Circulars (Folder 33: 7)
  - 1934 (Folder 33: 8)
- SERIES NO. 677. RECORDS OF CONSULAR ACTIVITIES
  - 1936
    - General (Folder 33: 9)
    - Funchal (Folder 33: 10)
    - Lisbon (Folder 33: 11)
    - Porto (Folder 33: 12)
  - 1937
    - General (Folder 33: 13)
    - Bilbao, Las Palmas, Malaga, Vigo (Folder 33: 14)
    - Lisbon (Folder 33: 15)
  - 1938
    - General (Folder 33: 16)
    - Funchal (Folder 33: 17)
  - 1939
    - Lisbon (Folder 33: 18)
    - Madeira (Folder 33: 19)
  - 1944-1946 (Folder 33: 20)
- SERIES NO. 678. INSPECTION OF REPRESENTATIONS ABROAD, 1936 (Folder 33: 21)
- SERIES NO. 686. FARES FOR CONSULAR SERVICES
  - 1934 (Folder 33: 22)
  - 1936 (Folder 33: 23)
  - 1938 (Folder 33: 24)
  - 1939 (Folder 33: 25)
- SERIES NO. 693a. INFORMATION ON LEGAL AND SOCIO-ECONOMIC SYSTEM OF OTHER COUNTRIES IN PUBLIC LAW
  - 1935 (Folder 33: 26)
  - 1938 (Box-folder 34: 1)
- SERIES NO. 693b. INFORMATION ON LEGAL AND SOCIO-ECONOMIC SYSTEM OF OTHER COUNTRIES IN CIVIL LAW
  - 1934 (Folder 34: 2)
  - 1935 (Folder 34: 3)
- SERIES NO. 694. ADMINISTRATIVE AND JUDICIARY REQUISITIONS, 1943 (Folder 34: 4)
- SERIES NO. 694a. ADMINISTRATIVE AND JUDICIARY REQUISITIONS. CIVIL AND TRADE MATTERS, 1933-1934 (Folder 34: 5)
- SERIES NO. 694b. ADMINISTRATIVE AND JUDICIARY REQUISITIONS. CRIMINAL MATTERS (EXTRADITIONS)
  - 1931-1936 - Goldreich vel Goldsztein (Folder 34: 6)
  - 1934-1935 - Ehrenfest, Fritz (Folder 34: 7)
  - 1935 (Folder 34: 8)
- SERIES NO. 695a. DELIVERY OF DOCUMENTS FROM POLAND, 1936 (Folder 34: 9)
- SERIES NO. 699. LEGALIZATION AND AUTHENTICATION
  - 1936 (Folder 34: 10)
  - 1939-1940 (Folder 34: 11)
  - 1940 (Folder 34: 12)
  - 1943 (Folder 34: 13)
- SERIES NO. 700. TRANSLATIONS
  - 1934-1935 - Jewish citizens (Folder 34: 14)
  - 1936 (Folder 34: 15)
  - 1937 (Folder 34: 16)
  - 1938 (Folder 34: 17)
- SERIES NO. 701. NOTARY FUNCTIONS, 1935 (Folder 34: 18)
- SERIES NO. 707. VITAL RECORDS. GENERAL
  - 1940 (Folder 34: 19)
  - 1941 (Folder 34: 20)
  - 1942 (Folder 34: 21)
  - 1943 (Folder 34: 22)
- SERIES NO. 707a. VITAL RECORDS. MARRIAGE (Box 35)
  - 1935 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - 1936 (Folder 35: 2)
- SERIES NO. 708b. VITAL RECORDS. LEGITIMATION, ADOPTION
  - 1934-1937 (Folder 35: 3)
  - 1937 (Folder 35: 4)
  - 1938 (Folder 35: 5)
- SERIES NO. 709a. COMPLAINTS OF POLISH CITIZENS TO AUTHORITIES AND INDIVIDUALS ABROAD
  - 1934-1936 (Folder 35: 6)
  - 1938 (Folder 35: 7)
- SERIES NO. 710. INHERITANCE AND WILLS
  - 1932-1938 - Krolikowski, Wlodzimierz (Folder 35: 8)
  - 1933-1934 - Jozefowicz, Aron (Folder 35: 9)
  - 1934 (Folder 35: 10)
  - 1934-1937 - Winter, Lina (Folder 35: 11)
  - 1937 (Folder 35: 12)
  - 1945 - Okoniewski, Stanislaw, Bishop (Folder 35: 13)
- SERIES NO. 712. DIPLOMATIC INTERVENTION ON BEHALF OF INDIVIDUALS
  - 1937 (Folder 35: 14)
  - 1940 (Folder 35: 15)
- SERIES NO. 715. CIVIC AFFAIRS. FUNDAMENTAL ISSUES
  - 1934-1937 (Folder 35: 16)
  - 1939-1940 (Folder 35: 17)
- SERIES NO. 717. ACKNOWLEDGEMENT OF POLISH CITIZENSHIP, 1939 (Folder 35: 18)
- SERIES NO. 718. ACQUISITION OF POLISH CITIZENSHIP, 1939 (Folder 35: 19)
- SERIES NO. 719. REVOCATION OF POLISH CITIZENSHIP, 1939 (Folder 35: 20)
- SERIES NO. 721. ACQUISITION OF FOREIGN CITIZENSHIP, 1938 (Folder 35: 21)
- SERIES NO. 728. PASSPORT REGULATIONS, 1942 (Folder 35: 22)
- SERIES NO. 729. ISSUANCE AND EXTENSION OF PASSPORTS, 1934-1939 (Folder 35: 23)
- SERIES NO. 729a. ISSUANCE AND EXTENSION OF PASSPORTS. REGULAR PASSPORTS, 1939 (Folder 35: 24)
- SERIES NO. 732. FOREIGNERS: THEIR ENTRY AND STAY IN POLAND. FUNDAMENTAL ISSUES
  - 1938 (Folder 35: 25)
  - 1939 - Noel, Leon - Szembek, Jan (Folder 35: 26)
- SERIES NO. 733. VISA REGULATIONS, 1939 (Folder 35: 27)
- SERIES NO. 735. POLISH VISAS (Box 36)
  - 1934-1935 (Folder 36: 1)
  - 1938 (Folder 36: 2)
- SERIES NO. 735a. POLISH VISAS. FINANCIAL REASONS, 1939 January-September (Folder 36: 3)
- SERIES NO. 736. BORDER TRAFFIC, 1939 (Folder 36: 4)
- SERIES NO. 737. GENERAL VISA POLICIES OF OTHER COUNTRIES
  - 1938 (Folder 36: 5)
  - 1939 (Folder 36: 6)
- SERIES NO. 738. REFUGEES
  - 1938 (Folder 36: 7)
  - 1939 (Folder 36: 8)
  - 1940
    - General (Folder 36: 9)
    - January-June (Folder 36: 10)
    - July-August - Police (Folder 36: 11)
    - September-October (Folder 36: 12)
    - November-December - Police. (Folder 36: 13)
      List
  - 1941
    - General
      - General (Folder 36: 14)
      - January-April (Folder 36: 15)
      - May-August (Folder 36: 16)
      - September-December (Folder 36: 17)
    - Technicians
      - January-June (Folder 36: 18)
      - July-December (Folder 36: 19)
  - 1942
    - General
      - General (Folder 36: 20)
      - January-April (Folder 36: 21)
      - May-August (Box-folder 37: 1)
      - September-December (Folder 37: 2)
    - Technicians (Folder 37: 3)
    - Visas. (Folder 37: 4)
      Includes letter from President Edward Raczkiewicz
  - 1943
    - General
      - January-June (Folder 37: 5)
      - July-December (Folder 37: 6)
    - Radziminski, Witold (Folder 37: 7)
    - Technicians. List (Folder 37: 8)
    - Visas
      - Canadian (Folder 37: 9)
      - Mexican (Folder 37: 10)
- SERIES NO. 741b. EXPULSION OF POLISH CITIZENS, 1939 (Folder 37: 11)
- SERIES NO. 745. MILITARY ISSUES
  - 1939 (Folder 37: 12)
  - 1940 (Folder 37: 13)
- SERIES NO. 746. MILITARY REGULATIONS
  - 1933-1935 (Folder 37: 14)
  - 1938 (Folder 37: 15)
- SERIES NO. 747. MILITARY RECORDS, 1939 (Folder 37: 16)
- SERIES NO. 749. POSTPONEMENT OF MILITARY SERVICE, 1939 (Folder 37: 17)
- SERIES NO. 750. FOREIGN CITIZENS IN POLISH MILITARY SERVICES, 1939 (Folder 37: 18)
- SERIES NO. 751. POLISH CITIZENS IN FOREIGN MILITARY SERVICES - Spanish Civil War. List, 1939 (Folder 37: 19)
- SERIES NO. 752. DESERTION AND AVOIDANCE OF MILITARY SERVICE, 1936 (Folder 37: 20)
- SERIES NO. 754. MEDALS AWARDED. List, 1940 (Box-folder 38: 1)
- SERIES NO. 755. POLISH ARMY ABROAD, 1943-1945 (Folder 38: 2)
- SERIES NO. 758. SURVEILLANCE
  - 1936 (Folder 38: 3)
  - 1943 - Middle East - Jewish deserters (Folder 38: 4)
  - 1944 (Folder 38: 5)
  - 1945 (Folder 38: 6)
- SERIES NO. 759. ARREST WARRANTS - Spanish Civil War participants, 1939 (Folder 38: 7)
- SERIES NO. 761. INFORMATION RELATED TO NATIONAL SECURITY, 1940-1942 (Folder 38: 8)
- SERIES NO. 761d. COMMUNISTS
  - 1935
    - General (Folder 38: 9)